Narasimharao Teegala (1) Featured

Software Engineer seeking assignment in developing web applications both frontend and backend using Rails Framework, React JS, Bootstrap, CSS, Postgresql, MySQL



Current Designation: Software Engineer Total Experience: 2 Year(s) 4 Month(s)

Current Company: GGK Technologies Notice Period: 2 Months

Current Location: Hyderabad / Secunderabad Highest Degree: B.Tech/B.E. [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Hyderabad Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: Software Engineer, Rails Framework, React JS, Bootstrap, CSS, Postgresql

Verified: Email - id Phone Number |

Last Active: 22-Jan-21 Last Modified: 22-Jan-21

Summary

Over 2+ years of Experience in Ruby on Rails, Postgresql, MySQL, MySQL Server, Bootstrap 3.0/3.3 and React JS, and Redux.

Most recent concentration has been the design of object - oriented web applications for client-server applications using Rails Framework, React JS, Bootstrap, CSS 3. Have 2+ years of experience on working with Ruby on Rails, Postgresql, my sql

Have 6 months of experience on working with python and flask

Experience in all phases of Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC) from Requirements gathering, Analysis, and Design, Development, Documentation, Testing, Implementation and

Maintenance of various Web based applications in Agile Methodology.

Experience in building different architectures in Ruby on rails and have strong

understanding of Data structures, Algorithms, Object-Oriented Design, Design patterns like

singleton, Factory

Work Experience

GGK Technologies as Software Engineer

Aug 2018 to Till Date

EWE Gas structured Trading suite: October 2020 to Present Technologies: python, flask, mongodb, reactjs, redux, power BI

Responsibilities:

Responsible for developing the API's based on the requirements.

Responsible for Application Deployment of React.

Discussion with client and giving suggestions for features while developing web application

Attending daily scrum call with clients

Developed front end features with react

Developed some reports using Power BI

Used GitLab for Version Control and JIRA for Task management.

Pronto Avenue Australia: Jan 2020 to Sept 2020

Technologies: jruby, Rails Framework, My SQL, HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, javascript and jQuery

Responsibilities:

Requirements gathering and discussing the work flows of each requirement.

Involved in sprint planning with estimates.

Discussion with the team about the implementation plan and providing inputs.

Writing unit tests using Rspecs

Developed front end with the html, css and bootstrap.

Innozation labs Cann ID: June 2019 to Dec 2019

Technologies: ruby, Rails Framework, react Js, redux, postgresql, heroku

Responsibilities:

Requirements gathering and discussing the work flows of each requirement.

Involved in sprint planning with estimates.

Discussion with the team about the implementation plan and providing inputs.

Attending daily stand up meeting with client

Developed the web application using ruby on rails

Peer code reviews and providing suggestions.

Used Github for Version Control and JIRA for Task management.

Shopkeep backoffice: Aug 2018 to May 2019

Role: Ruby on Rails Developer

Technologies: ruby, Rails Framework, react js, redux, postgresql

Responsibilities:

Involved in sprint planning.

Discuss the stories within the team and post questions to the business team.

Attending daily stand up meeting with client. Developed web applications using ruby on rails

Written unit test cases using Rspec

Used Bitbucket for Version Control and JIRA for Task management.

Education

UG: B.Tech/B.E. (Computers) from vishnu institute of technology in 2018

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Ruby, python, SQL	
MySQL, SQL Server, postgresql,	
neo4j, mongodb	
Visual Studio, visual studio code	
React JS, Redux, Java Script, HTML, CSS	
Ruby on Rails, Flask, Django	
GIT	

Affirmative Action

Physically Challenged: No Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time

Work Authorization